Paul Bigelow Sears Collection, 1832-1969 (bulk 1930-1966) MS 455
University of Arizona
Paul Bigelow Sears Collection 1832-1969 1930-1966 (bulk)
Collection Number: MS 455
Sears, Paul B. (Paul Bigelow), 1891-1990
6.5 Linear Feet
The collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, grant proposals, reports, photographs, subject files, field notes, pollen samples and data relating to desert ecology which document Paul Sear's career as a botanist, ecologist and educator. The bulk of the collection is comprised of correspondence between Sears and other researchers. Ecology was the central interest of Paul B. Sears' professional life. Understanding an ecosystem includes understanding its history. Sears used pollen analysis data of bog sediments as a tool, as a means to reconstruct past vegetation and to infer climate which is included in this collection.
Special Collections, University Libraries University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
None
Biographical Note
Paul Bigelow Sears, educator, botanist, ecologist and conservationist was born on December 17, 1891, in Bucyrus, Ohio, to Rufus Victor and Sallie Harris Sears. He attended Ohio Wesleyan University, receiving a B.S. degree in 1913 and a B.A. in 1914. From there he went to the University of Nebraska and received an M.A. in 1915, after which he studied at the University of Chicago, earning his Ph.D. in botany in 1922. Sears married Marjorie Lea McCutcheon on June 22, 1917, and served in the United States Army from 1917-1918. The Sears’ had three children, Paul McCutcheon, Catherine Louise (Mrs. Arthur Frazer), and Sallie Harris Sears.
Sears began his teaching career as an instructor in botany at Ohio State University (1915-1919). He then served as assistant and associate professor of botany at the University of Nebraska (1919-1927). From 1928 to 1938 Sears taught at the University of Oklahoma and was head of the Botany Department. He also served as a botanist for the State Biological Survey of Oklahoma. His books from these years presented issues in the study of ecology to the public. These included Deserts On The March (1935), for which Sears received a Book of the Month award, This Is Our World (1937), and Who Are These Americans (1939). Sears also produced ecology study guides and textbooks for science teachers and their students.
From 1938 until 1950, Sears served as professor of botany at Oberlin College. In Ohio, Sears was active in local conservation groups and was instrumental in the founding of Friends of the Land in Ohio. In 1946 he was named to the Ohio Conservation Commission and worked to create an Ohio Department of Natural Resources. Sears was also active in the Ecological Society of America and was elected president of the society in 1948.
In 1950 Sears was named professor of conservation and chairman of the Conservation Program at Yale University. The Conservation Program at Yale was the country's first graduate program in the conservation of natural resources. From 1953 - 1955 Sears also served as chairman of the Plant Science Department at Yale. In 1952 Sears received the Conservation medal from the Garden Club of America and in 1956 he was named Eminent Botanist by the Botanical Society of America. Sears served as president of the American Association for the Advancement of Science (1956), Sigma Xi national lecturer (1956), chairman of the board the National Audubon Society (1956-1959), and president of the American Society of Naturalists (1959). From 1958 - 1964, Sears was a member of the National Science Board and from 1959 - 1972 he served on the Plowshare Advisory Committee of the Atomic Energy Commission.
In 1960 Sears retired from Yale and was named professor emeritus. Subsequently he served as visiting professor in the Tom Wallace Chair of Conservation at the University of Louisville and was a visiting faculty member at the University of Hawaii, Carleton College, Wake Forest College, and the University of Southern Illinois. From 1963 - 1965 Sears chaired the commission on science education of the American Association for the Advancement of Science. In 1965 Sears was named Eminent Ecologist by the Ecological Society of America. During the decade of the 1960s Sears published Where There Is Life (1962), The Living Landscape (1966), and Lands Beyond the Forest (1969), as well as writing articles of technical and general interest on applied ecology.
Paul B. Sears, perhaps more than any other person, epitomized American plant ecology. In a professional career spanning almost 7 decades, he made major contributions to vegetation mapping, paleoecology and Pleistocene history, vegetation studies, conservation, human ecology and our use of land; and particularly, the varied roles of scientists in modern society. He was one of the most respected and honored ecologists in North America. He died in the medical center at Plaza de Retiro in Taos, New Mexico on April 30, 1990.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series.
Series List
Series I: Correspondence, 1925-1969
Subseries 1: Incoming, 1927-1969
Subseries 2: Outgoing, 1927-1969
Subseries 3: Others, 1925-1968
Series II: Manuscripts and Publications, 1934-1967
Series III: Research Files, 1832-1967
Subseries 1: Geographic Locations – State, 1915-1966
Subseries 2: Geographic Locations – Country, 1948-1967
Subseries 3: Subjects, 1832-1960
Subseries 4: Activity Files, 1945-1966
Subseries 5: People, 1911-1959
Subseries 6: Field Notes, 1916-1961
The collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, grant proposals, reports, photographs, subject files, field notes, pollen samples and data relating to desert ecology which document Paul Sear's career as a botanist, ecologist and educator. The bulk of the collection is comprised of correspondence between Sears and other researchers. The collection also includes research reports and manuscripts written by Sears and other researchers; activity files of various meetings and conferences attended by Sears and field notes of peat and pollen data collected and analyzed in different states, Mexico and Canada.
Sears, Paul B. (Paul Bigelow), 1891-1990 - Correspondence; Botany – Research – United States; Botany – Research – Mexico; Botany – Research – Canada; Ecology – Research – United States; Ecology – Research – Mexico; Ecology – Research – Canada; Desert ecology – United States; Pollen – Research – United States; Pollen – Research – Mexico; Pollen – Research – Canada
- Series I: Correspondence,1920-1969
  This series is subdivided alphabetically by outgoing, incoming and other correspondence. It contains letters to and from Paul Sears and letters regarding Paul Sears written by others.
  - Subseries 1: Incoming,1927-1969
    - A, 1935-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B, 1931-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Ca-Cl, 1935-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Co-Cu, 1931-1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - D, 1927-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - E, 1934-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - F, 1934-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - G, 1931-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - H, 1934-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - I, 1937-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - J, 1935-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - K, 1932-1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - L, 1928-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - M, 1931-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - N, 1931-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - O, 1939-1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - P, 1935-1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - R, 1931-1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Sa-Sh, 1934-1964 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Sm-Sz, 1935-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - T, 1931-1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - V, 1934-1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - W, 1927-1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Z, 1948-1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 2: Outgoing, 1927-1969
    - A, 1935-1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - B, 1934-1967 (Box 2, Fodler 2)
    - Ca-Ch, 1927-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - D, 1935-1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - E, 1936-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - F, 1928-1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - G, 1932-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - H, 1932-1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - I, 1952-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - J, 1931-1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - K, 1933-1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - L, 1933-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - M, 1935-1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - N, 1936-1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - O, 1939-1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - P, 1935-1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - R, 1934-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Sa-Sl, 1935-1968 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Sm-Sz, 1939-1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - T, 1934-1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - U, 1937-1960 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - V, 1935-1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - W, 1928-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Y, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Z, 1952-1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 3: Others,1925-1968
    - A, 1936-1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - B, 1935-1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - C, 1935-1958 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - D, 1936-1961 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - E, 1938-1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - F, 1938-1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - G, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - H, 1937-1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - I, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - J, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - K, 1933-1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - L, 1935-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - M, 1952-1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - N, 1939-1955 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - O, 1925-1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - P, 1937-1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - R, 1939-1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - S, 1936-1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - T, 1936-1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - U, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - V, 1936-1943 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - W, 1939-1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Y, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Z, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Series II: Manuscripts and Publications,1934-1967
  This series contains written reports and publications by Paul Sears regarding his research and studies on pollen, palynology, climatic changes and plant ecology.
  - Bog Formation (Moor–Bildung) in Mexico, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Botany - Plant Ecology, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Climatic Changes in the Basin of Mexico, July 4, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Constructive Evidence of Climatic Change in the Prairie States, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Euphorbia Marginata, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Evidences of Recent Climatic Changes in Arkansas, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Determination of World Plant Formations from Simple Climatic Data, April 1, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Evidences of Climatic Changes in Oklahoma, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - The Green World of Charles Darwin, August 24, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Literature, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - NRC Committee on Paleobotany, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Paleobotanical Publications, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Palynologie Report, July 31, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Palynology in North America – A Current Report, 1961 (Box 3, Fodler 39)
  - Palynology in Southern North America II-V, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Plenary Sessions of Palynologists at the 8th International Congress of Botany, Paris, 2-14 July, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Pollen and Spore Circular No. 13, December 1946 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Pollen Spectra Associated with the Madison County Mastodon Site, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Pollens Frequent in Post Wisconsin Bogs, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - A Preliminary Report on Fossil Pollen of the Pleistocene in Mexico and New Mexico, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Report on the Ecology of Door Peninsula, Wisconsin, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Soil – A Basic Resource, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - World Report on Paleobotany, 1961-1967 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Series III: Research Files
  This series is subdivided by geographic locations, subjects, activity files, people and field notes. All but field notes are arranged alphabetically. Field notes are arranged chronologically. It contains pollen analysis, pollen and bog counts, reports written by researchers, conferences and meetings attended by Paul Sears and field notebooks containing pollen data.
  - Subseries 1: Geographic Locations – State, 1915-1966
    - Arizona – Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Arizona – Counts, 1928-1936 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Arizona – Diagrams, 1934-1956 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Arizona - Tucson, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Arkansas - Counts, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Arkansas – Diagrams, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - California – Counts, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - California – Diagrams, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Colorado – Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Colorado – Counts, 1925-1936 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Colorado – Diagrams, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Connecticut – Counts, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Connecticut – Diagrams, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Connecticut – Guilford, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Florida – Counts, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Florida – Diagrams and Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Georgia – Diagrams and Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Georgia – Report on Excavation at Irensmound, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Illinois – Counts, December 14, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Illinois – Diagrams, 1935-1960 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Illinois – Gray’s Lake, 1935-1956 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Illinois – Gray’s Lake, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Illinois – Gray’s Lake – Pollen Analysis, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Illinois – Gray’s Lake, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Indiana – Counts, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Indiana – Manuscripts, March 11, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Iowa – Correspondence, June 15, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Iowa – Counts, 1934-1958 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Iowa – Diagrams, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Kansas – Correspondence, February, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Massachusetts – Correspondence, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Massachusetts – Diagrams – Tables – Counts, 1939/1958 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Michigan – Counts, 1931-1935 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Michigan – Diagrams, 1930-1935 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Michigan – Manuscripts, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Minnesota – Correspondence, 1937-1946 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Minnesota – Counts, 1931-1935 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Minnesota – Counts, 1931-1935 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Minnesota – Diagrams, 1931-1935 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Nebraska – Correspondence, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Nebraska – Counts – Notes, 1960 (Box 3, File 89)
    - Nebraska – Crane Lake, January 21, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Nebraska – Diagrams and Tables, undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Nebraska – Hackberry Lake, January 24, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Nebraska – Krause Bog, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Nevada – Caves – Counts, undated (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Nevada – Caves – Diagrams, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Nevada – Caves – Notes and Correspondence, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Nevada – Summary Counts – Checked, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - New Hampshire – Correspondence and Counts, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - New Mexico – Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - New Mexico – Counts – Valle Grande – San Augustin, 1950-1956 (Box 4, File 5)
    - New Mexico – Data, 1955-1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - New Mexico – Diagrams – Tables, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - New Mexico – General Correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - New York – Correspondence - Manuscript, 1941-1956 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - New York – Long Island - Peat Deposit – G. B. Sowers and C. Franc Letters, etc., 1941-1956 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - North Carolina – Correspondence, 1941-1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Ohio – Bucyrus – Diagrams, 1935-1955 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Ohio – Castalla, 1952-1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Ohio – Castalia – Counts, 1952-1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Ohio – Castalia – Diagrams, 1955-1965 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Ohio – Castalia - Maps, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Ohio – Castalia – Notes, 1915-1966 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Ohio - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Ohio – Counts, 1935-1965 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Ohio – Data, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Oklahoma – Counts, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Oklahoma – Diagrams, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Pacific Coast – Counts, undated (Box 4, File 23)
    - Pennsylvania – Counts, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Pennsylvania – Diagrams, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Rhode Island – Maps, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - South Dakota – Correspondence – Counts, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Tennessee – Counts, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Tennessee – Diagrams and Tables, 1934-1951 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Texas – Correspondence, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Texas – Counts, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Utah – Ogden – Correspondence, etc., 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Virginia – Counts, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - West Virginia – Counts, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Wisconsin – Counts, 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Wyoming – Counts, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Wyoming – Diagrams, 1933-1937 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Subseries 2: Geographic Locations – Country, 1948-1967
    - Canada – Counts, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Canada – Diagrams, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Central America and Mexico – Correspondence, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Greenland – Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Jordan – Pella – Counts, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Mexico – Counts, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Mexico – Diagrams and Tables, 1950-1962 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Mexico – General correspondence, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Mexico – General correspondence, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Mexico – Miscellaneous, 1948-1955 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Mexico and New Mexico – Miscellany, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Mexico – Notes, etc., 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - South America – Correspondence, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Subseries 3: Subjects, 1832-1960
    - Bibliographies on Pollen Analysis, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bog Development, 1923-1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Botanical Gazette, 1938-1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Chronology, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Climate, 1931-1933 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Clippings Related to Fossil Pollen, 1937-1951 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Collections, 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Collections – Pollen, 1930-1948 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Electronic Flash – Illumination for Photomicrography, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Fossil Pollen in Peat Bogs in Northeastern North America by Preston Smith, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Geological Survey, 1951-1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Ice Profiles, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - International Committee on Palynology, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Literature – Pollen, 1908-1933 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Map Information, 1947-1958 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Michillinda, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - National Science Foundation, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Nuclear Science and Engineering Corporation, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Owl Swamps – Counts and Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Peat, 1931-1934 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Peat – German Pictures – Sphagum, 1899-1904 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Pelargonium Pollen Notes, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Pleistocene, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Pollen, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Pollen Abstracts, 1922-1926 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Pollen Analysis, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Pollen Analysis Circular, no. 1-8, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Pollen and Spore Circular, 9, 10 and 11, 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Pollen and Spore Circular, 12, 13 and 14, 1945-1952 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Pollen and Spore Circular, 13, 14, 15 and 17, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Pollen – Bibliography, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Pollen Grants and Requests, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Pollen – Icons, 1832-1927 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Pollen Investigations – Notes – Miscellany, 1920-1959 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Pollen Keys, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Pollen – Maps – Bog Locations in N.E. North America, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Pollen Notes, 1882-1935 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Pollen Notes – Miscellaneous, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Pollen Photos, 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Pollen – Plant, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Pollen Profiles, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Pollen Research Budget, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Pollen Structure, 1926-1928 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Pollen Workers – International Address List, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Quarternary Climate, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Research, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Sampling – Soil Testing Services, Inc. – MJA Corp., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Species Ranges, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - S.W. Palynology, 1960 (Box 5, File 49)
    - Technique, 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Tree Rings, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Western Speleological Institute, 1957-1960 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Yale University and Oberlin – Cooperating, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Zempoala Pollen Analysis, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4: Activity Files, 1945-1966
    - Friends of Pleistocene Geology 22nd Reunion, May 15-17, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Friends of Pleistocene Geology Meeting at London, Ontario, 1945 Annual Meetings (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Geological Society of America, May 16-17, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Geological Society of America – Fifty-Eighth Annual Meeting – Hotel William Penn, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, Dec. 27-29, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - International Conference on Palynology, Tucson, AZ, April 1962 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - International Conference on Palynology, Utrecht, August 29-September 3, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Mailing List of Paleobotanists, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Members of the Paleobotanical Section, Botanical Society of America, January 7, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Minutes of Annual Business Meeting, Paleobotanical Section, Botanical Society Of America, January 7, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Paleobotanical Section, Fellow Members, April 6, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Paleobotanical Section, Field Trip, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Paleobotanical Section of the Botanical Society of America, Membership List, 1959; 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Palynology Symposium, Yale University, Feb. 21, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Pleistocene Questionnaire, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Pollen Conference, Aug. 1956 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Report of a Conference to Plan Coordinated Anthropological Research in the Valley Of Mexico, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Second National Pollen Conference, Dec. 28-29, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Third National Pollen Conference, Oberlin, May 1956 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Wenner-G ren Foundation, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Yale University and Oberlin Cooperating, Grant Applications, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Subseries 5: People, 1911-1959
    - Antevs, Ernst, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Barkley, Fred A., undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Boyko, Hugo, 1921-1943 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Campbell, Thomas D., 1948 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Clisby, Kathryn H., undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Clisby, P. J. and Kathryn., 1911-1953 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Conner, Ruth Ann, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Eckerson, S. H., 1926 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Ennis, David B., undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Fanshawe, John R., undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Folger and Thomson, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Fuechsel, C. F., 1957 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Grayson, John F., undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Hafsten, Ulf, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Hammen, T. van der, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Hansen, Henry P., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Harrison, A. E., undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Iverson, Johannes, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Johnson, L. E., undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Kaiser, M., 1955 (Box 6, Folder 45)